Finding Aid for the Ruth St. Denis Papers LSC.1031
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1886-1968
  - Subseries 2.3: Correspondence, 1886-1968
    - 1903-1904, 1911, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; Denis, Thomas Laban; St. Denis, Brother (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - 1916, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; Denis, Thomas Laban (Box 45, Folder 6)
      Handwritten letters primarily between Ruth's mother Ruth Emma Hull Dennis, and her father Thomas Laban Dennis while they resided at Bishops Sanitarium in Pasadena and the Soldier's Home in Sawtelle, respectively. Also letters between Ruth, her mother and father, as well as correspondence between her father and his friends.
    - 1918, 1920-1929 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      Primarily letters to Ruth from dance companies, theaters, schools, and other arts organizations regarding performances, appearances, and dances.
    - 1918, 1932, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; St. Denis, Brother; Denis, Thomas Laban (Box 45, Folder 7)
      Primarily letters, sympathy cards, and telegrams regarding the death of Ruth's mother, Ruth Emma Hull Dennis. Some letters from Buzz Dennis, Ted Shawn, newspaper clippings and obituaries, as well as photos of Ruth's mother. Letters to Thomas Laban Denis regarding his Civil War pensions.
    - 1920-1929, Wheeler, Pearl (Box 46, Folder 3)
      Primarily correspondence between Ruth and Pearl Wheeler.
    - 1927-1949, Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972 (Box 123, Folder 3)
      Mostly letters between Ruth and diverse people and organizations, discussing a variety of topics. Some correspondence between Ruth and Ted Shawn. Includes some writings and "history letters" by Ruth that she sent to various people to keep them up to date with her plans and activities.
    - 1932, Dennis, Ruth Emma Hull; St. Denis, Brother (Box 45, Folder 8)
      Primarily letters and telegrams regarding the death of Ruth's mother, Ruth Emma Hull Dennis. Some letters between Ruth and her brother, Buzz Dennis (also known as Brother St. Denis).
    - 1938 June-July (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Letters to Ruth from Brother Don, Krishna Lal Shridharani, and Kendall K. Mussey. Also includes a program by the Hindustan Association of America.
    - 1939 April, Graham, Martha; Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993; March, Fredric, 1897-1975; Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974; Hepburn, Katharine, 1907-2003; Taylor, Deems, 1885-1966 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      Letters from Ruth to various figures inviting them for tea to discuss an upcoming Moral Re-Armament meeting. Recipients include Martha Graham, Helen Hayes, Fredric March, Katherine Hepburn among others. Only includes responses from some.
    - 1930-1939, Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972; St. Denis, Brother; Wheeler, Pearl; Lowrey, Edward W. (Box 46, Folder 1, 4-6, 8)
      Primarily letters between Ruth and various people and organizations, including Pearl Wheeler, Ted Shawn, Brother St. Denis and "Wilson". Personal and fan letters written to Ruth. Contracts for appearances and engagements under her agent, Edward W. Lowrey. Letters from Ruth's secretary to potential sponsors for the Chicago World's Fair. Solicitations sent out to colleges regarding dance performances.
    - 1940, 1957-1959 (Box 151, Folder 6)
      Mostly letters between Ruth and diverse people and organizations, discussing a variety of topics. Also includes writings by Ruth.
    - 1945 October 3, Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972 (Box 153, Folder 5)
      One letter to Ruth from Ted Shawn where he goes into detail about a difficult summer and his plans during his upcoming travels to New York.
    - 1940-1949, Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972; St. Denis, Brother (Box 46, Folder 9-12, Box 47, Folder 1-3)
      Primarily letters between Ruth and various people and organizations, including Ted Shawn and Brother St. Denis. Includes some writing by Ruth, as well as "history letters" which she wrote to various colleagues and friends to keep them up to date with her plans and activities.
    - 1947-1948, Ida, Marshall (Box 47, Folder 4)
      Primarily handwritten letters to Ruth from Ida Marshall.
    - 1953 November 25 (Box 153, Folder 6)
      Letters from Mildred Rice of the Ruth St. Denis Studio to Mr. Robert Saudek of the Ford Foundation, Ed Sullivan of Toast of the Town, and Dodd Mead & Co. Publishers regarding Ruth's availability for appearances on television.
    - 1950-1959, Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972; Skipper, William; St. Denis, Brother; Meller, Harro; Adelphi College; St. John, Aubrey (Box 47, Folder 5-7, Box 48, Folder 1-7, Box 49, Folder 1-6, Box 123, Folder 4-5)
      Primarily letters between Ruth and various people and organizations, including Ted Shawn, William Skipper, Harro Meller, Brother St. Denis (also known as Buzz), DANCE Magazine, and Adelphi College. Some letters were sent by Aubrey St. John on behalf of Ruth. Also writings by Ruth, including "history letters" that she sent to various people to keep them up to date with her plans and activities.
    - 1959-1964, Skipper, William; Meller, Harro; Todd, Arthur. (Box 52, Folder 6)
      Primarily letters and greeting cards between Ruth and a variety of people and organizations, including William Skipper, Harro Meller, and Arthur Todd.
    - 1960 November 1, 1961 June 27 (Box 153, Folder 7)
      Letters to Ruth from fans.
    - 1962, 1965, Todd, Arthur.; Stury, Alfred Frantz; Dougherty, John, 1910-1988; Ruth St. Denis Center (Box 51, Folder 7)
      Letter from Arthur Todd to William Schuman. Postcards to Ruth from friends, as well as an invitation from Adelphi College. Letters between Ruth and Alfred Frantz Stury and John Dougherty of the Ruth St. Denis Center.
    - 1963, Stury, Alfred Frantz; Ruth St. Denis Center (Box 53, Folder 6)
      Mostly correspondence between Ruth and Alfred Frantz Stury, director of the Ruth St. Denis Center. Some letters between Ruth's secretary, Bernice Andres and others.
    - 1964, Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972; Stury, Alfred Frantz; Pinska, Klarna; Ruth St. Denis Center (Box 50, Folder 3, Box 52, Folder 8)
      Primarily letters to Ruth from various people and organizations, including Ted Shawn. Some correspondence between Ruth St. Denis Center (Ruth, Alfred Frantz Stury or a secretary) and Klarna Pinska.
    - 1964, Stury, Alfred Frantz; Pinska, Klarna (Box 52, Folder 8)
      Mostly correspondence between the Ruth St. Denis Center (to or by Ruth, Alfred Frantz Stury, or a secretary) and Klarna Pinska.
    - 1965 (Box 53, Folder 7, Box 153, Folder 8)
      Primarily letters to Ruth by diverse people and organizations, discussing a variety of topics. Includes some black and white photographs of Ruth, as well as her writings. Some letters undated.
    - 1960-1965, Stury, Alfred Frantz; Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972; Skipper, William; Adelphi College; Ruth St. Denis Center; St. John, Aubrey (Box 52, Folder 5, 7, Box 55, Folder 1)
      Primarily letters and greeting cards between Ruth and a variety of people and organizations, including William Skipper, Ted Shawn, Aubrey St. John, Adelphi College, and Drake University. Also letters between Alfred B. Stury and a variety of entities on behalf of Ruth as director of the Ruth St. Denis Center.
    - 1960-1968, Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972; Meller, Harro; Skipper, William; St. Denis, Brother; Stury, Alfred Frantz; Pinska, Klarna; Dougherty, John, 1910-1988; Ruth St. Denis Center; Adelphi College (Box 50, Folder 1-2, 4-6, Box 51, Folder 1-6, Box 52, Folder 1, Box 53, Folder 3, 5, Box 54, Folder 1-5, Box 123, Folder 7)
      Primarily letters between Ruth and diverse people and organizations, discussing a variety of topics. Correspondents include Ted Shawn, William Skipper, Harro Meller, Brother St. Denis (also known as Buzz), Adelphi College, UCLA, John Dougherty, and Klarna Pinska. Several letters from the director of the Ruth St. Denis Center, Alfred Frantz Stury, to various entities.
    - 1960-1968, Stury, Alfred Frantz; Ruth St. Denis Center (Box 123, Folder 6)
      Mostly writings by Ruth, including "history letters" that she sent to various people to keep them up to date with her plans and activities. Some correspondence between members of the Ruth St. Denis Center.
    - 1962-1963, Stury, Alfred Frantz; Ruth St. Denis Center; Skipper, William; St. John, Aubrey; Adelphi College; Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972 (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
      Primarily letters between the director of the Ruth St. Denis Center, Alfred B. Stury and a variety of entities. Some correspondence between Ruth and William Skipper, Aubrey St. John of Adelphi College, and Ted Shawn.
    - 1962-1963, 1967, Stury, Alfred Frantz; Ruth St. Denis Center; Skipper, William; St. John, Aubrey; Adelphi College; Dougherty, John, 1910-1988 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      Primarily letters between the director of the Ruth St. Denis Center, Alfred B. Stury and a variety of entities. Some correspondence between Ruth and William Skipper, Aubrey St. John of Adelphi College, Drake University, and John Dougherty.
    - 1962-1964, Stury, Alfred Frantz; Adelphi College; Ruth St. Denis Center (Box 52, Folder 9)
      Mostly correspondence between Alfred Frantz Stury and a variety of entities on behalf of Ruth as director of the Ruth St. Denis Center. Includes letters to and by the American Guild of Musical Artists and the Canadian Broadcasting Corporations. Also letters between the Ruth St. Denis Center and Barbara Andres from Adelphi College.
    - 1964-1966, Skipper, William; Shawn, Ted, 1891-1972; Thornburg, Forrest (Box 53, Folder 4)
      Primarily letters between Ruth and various people and organizations, including William Skipper, Forrest Thornburg, and Ted Shawn.
    - undated, Skipper, William; St. John, Aubrey (Box 55, Folder 2-4, Box 56, Folder 1-5, Box 57, Folder 2-9, Box 123, Folder 9)
      Mostly letters between Ruth and diverse people and organizations, discussing a variety of topics. Correspondents include William Skipper and Aubrey St. John. Includes some writings and "history letters" by Ruth that she sent to various people to keep them up to date with her plans and activities.
    - undated, Stury, Alfred Frantz (Box 57, Folder 1)
      One letter by Alfred Frantz Stury, director of the Ruth St. Denis Center regarding "Ruth St. Denis Lecture Films."
    - undated (Box 123, Folder 9)
- Series 3: Writings, 1900s-1968
  The writings series contains essays and manuscripts of St. Denis's autobiography, An Unfinished Life; poems; and lectures and speeches written by St. Denis, Ted Shawn, and other associates. Much of this material focuses on expressing spirituality through dance. St. Denis also examined the ways in which dancing and movement can enhance lives on an individual and national basis. There are multiple drafts of some essays and manuscripts, including St. Denis's autobiography, that provide insight into St. Denis's writing process. This series also contains inventories of St. Denis's writings.
  - Subseries 3.1: Essays and manuscripts, 1910s-1960s
    Contains multiple copies of the manuscript for Ruth St. Denis's autobiography, An Unfinished Life, and Ted Shawn's book about St. Denis, Pioneer and Prophet.
    - An Unfinished Life, part II, undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - An Unfinished Life, part IV, undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - An Unfinished Life, 1914-1932 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - An Unfinished Life, undated (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - An Unfinished Life, part I, undated (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Ruth St. Denis autobiography, 1936 April 6 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1910s-1920s (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1930s (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - An Unfinished Life pages, 1930s (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - An Unfinished Life (2 of 2), 1930s (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - An Unfinished Life (1 of 2), 1930s (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1930s-1940s (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1940s (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1950s (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1950s (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1950s (Box 64, Folder 1)
      Includes "Wisdom Comes Dancing" and "Current Biography."
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1950s (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1950s (Box 64, Folder 3)
      Includes "What is the Religious Dance?," "Current Biography," "Lecture for Connecticut College," "Traditional and Metaphysical Forms of Religious Dance," and journals.
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1965 March 1 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1960s (Box 64, Folder 5)
      Includes "Rhythms on the Mound," "Intercourse Ultimates," "Woman Speaks," and handwritten, hand-bound notes.
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1960s (Box 64, Folder 6)
      Includes "My Ambition," "Science of Man," "The Letter," and writings about balanced government.
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1960s (Box 64, Folder 7)
      Includes "Angels of Liturgy," "Balanced Government," and "A Manual of Healing."
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1957-1966 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Includes handwritten notes for "Science of Man" and "Rhythms for Traditional Worship in Christian Church."
    - Essays and manuscripts, 1960s (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Includes writings about balanced government, "Rhythms of the Resurrection," "The Church" handwritten notes, and "Inferno."
    - Essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Includes biographical writings including notes for "An Unfinished Life," "Dialogue for a Temple," and miscellaneous writings.
    - Essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Includes handwritten notes and miscellaneous writings.
    - Essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 65, Folder 5)
      Includes "A Theater of Philosophy," "Creative Arts Colony," and miscellaneous writings.
    - Essays and manuscripts: Misc., undated (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Essays and manuscripts: Misc., undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
      Includes "Dialogue for a Temple."
    - Essays and manuscripts: Misc., undated (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Essays and manuscripts: Misc., undated (Box 66, Folder 3)
      Includes "Dialogue for a Temple" and biographical writings.
    - Essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Autobiography, Ruth's copy No. 1, 1936 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Autobiography, Ruth's copy No. 2, 1936 (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Writings, 1965 September (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Writings, undated (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Autobiography pages, Journals 1960 August, miscellaneous writings, 1950s-1960s (Box 125, Folder 9)
    - Writings, 1950s-1960s (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Writings, 1919-1920s (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Writings, 1925-1951 (Box 120, Folder 9)
    - Writings, 1920s-1930s (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Divine Dance by Ruth St. Denis, 1933 (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - Writings, 1930s-1940s (Box 120, Folder 12)
    - Writings, 1940s (Box 120, Folder 13)
    - Writings, 1950s (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Writings, 1950s (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Writings, 1950 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      Includes "Delsarte's Law of Correspondence," "Light Bringers," "Creative Silence," and "Private Wars."
    - Writings, 1960s (Box 121, Folder 4)
      Includes "World Peace Blitz" by John McConnell, St. Denis speeches, and misc religious and philosophical dance writings.
    - "Balanced Government", 1966 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Writings, 1960s (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Writings, 1960s (Box 122, Folder 1)
    - Writings, undated (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Writings, undated (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Writings, undated (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Writings, undated (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - Writings, undated (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Writings, undated (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - Writings, undated (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Writings, 1930s-1960s, undated (Box 151, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3.2: Poems, 1910s-1960s
    Includes poetry that St. Denis wrote throughout her career.
    - Poems, 1910s-1950s (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Poems, 1930s (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Poems, 1940s (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Poems, 1950s (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Poems, 1960s (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Poems, undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Poems, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Poems, undated (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Poems, undated (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Poems by Dr. Rudolf Steiner, 1911-1922, undated (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3.3: Lectures and speeches, 1930s-1960s
    Contains lectures that St. Denis gave to classes she taught and transcripts of speeches she gave throughout her career.
    - Speeches and lectures, 1930s-1940s (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Speeches and lectures, 1950s (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Speeches and lectures, 1950s-1960s (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Speeches and lectures, undated (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Class in Instantaneous Healing, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3.4: Writings by St. Denis's associates, 1910s-1960s
    Contains essays, poems, and publications written by Ted Shawn, William Skipper, other members of St. Denis's company, and other dancers, as well as a published copy of Ted Shawn's book about St. Denis, Pioneer and Prophet.
    - Original Pioneer and Prophet manuscript, circa 1910s (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - St. Denis: Pioneer and Prophet by Ted Shawn, circa 1910s (Box 164)
    - The Dance of Life by Havelock Ellis, chapter 2, 1923 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, 1920s (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, 1930s (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, 1940s (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Child of the Son, second draft, 1952 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Ruth St. Denis: An Attempt by Harro Meller, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, 1950s (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, 1960s (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - The Dance: Its Origin, Psychology and Philosophy by John H. Manas, undated (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Tender Touch by Peter Quigley, one act play, undated (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Other people's essays and manuscripts, undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Other people's poems, 1920s-1960s (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Other people's poems, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Plays by John Dearing, 1963 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Other people's plays, undated (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Other people's plays, undated (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Other people's plays, undated (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - 2 books: The American Stage of Today, 1910; 2 copies (Box 164)
  - Subseries 3.5: Inventories of writings, 1920s-1960s
    Contains lists of St. Denis's essays and poems.
    - Inventories of poems and speeches and lectures, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Inventories of essays and manuscripts, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Literature IV, 1920-1949 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Literature, Love VI, 1925-1944 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Literature III, 1930s-1940s (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Literature II, essays, 1934-1950 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Lists of writings, 1910s-1960s (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Inventory of writings, undated (Box 129, Folder 2)
- Series 4: Performance and dance materials, 1910s-1960s
  This series contains materials for choreography and performance notes for many of St. Denis's dances from the second half of her career. This includes dance dramas; performance sketches and artwork; sketches of costumes and stage designs; program schedules; "Oriental dance" materials; performance research and resources; education and dance center materials that relate to the Denishawn School, School of Divine Dance, Society of Spiritual Arts Church, Creative Arts Colony, Temple materials, and Rhythmic Choir; and sheet music. These materials provide insight into how St. Denis developed her dances and the methods she use to communicate ideas to her students.
  - Subseries 4.1: Choreography and performance notes, 1910s-1960s
    Contains materials for dance dramas, performances sketches and artwork depicting costumes and set designs, program schedules, and "Oriental dance" materials from the Denishawn Dancers' tour of Asia.
    - Materials for divine dance, 1910s-1920s (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - "The Isle of Death", 1915-1964 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Smaller ballets, 1917-1920 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Dance-Dramas by Ruth St. Denis, 1925 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1920s-1940s (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Ballets, 1920s-1960s (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1930s (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - "Rhada: A Hindu Temple Dance", 1939 August (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Ballets by Ruth St. Denis, from years 1904-1930, 1948 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Ballets, book 1, part 1, 1948 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1940s (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1940s (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1940s-1950s (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Dance dramas, 1950s (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Materials for divine dance, 1950s (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - "The Light of Asia", 1954 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - "Freedom", 1955 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Materials for divine dance, 1960s (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1960s (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Performance notes, 1964 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Ballets, Book 1, Part 2, undated (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Dance dramas, undated (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Dance dramas, undated (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - The Festival of Light, undated (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - "The Prophetess", undated (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - "Babylon", undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - "The Woman and the Dragon", undated (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - "The Ballet of Light", undated (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - "The Lamp", undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Boston Arts Festival Script, 1961 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - "The Love God", 1964 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - "Songs of Solomon", undated (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - "The Ballet of Light", undated (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - "Dawn over Sion", undated (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - "The Battle for Peace", undated (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - "Amphetryon", undated (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Choreography, undated (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - "David" dance drama, undated (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - "The Woman and the Dragon", undated (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - "The Prophetess", undated (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Dance dramas, 1962 (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - "Akhnaton", undated (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - "Oriental dance" materials, undated (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Program and performance schedules, 1910s-1960s, undated (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Performance sketches, 1929-1960s, undated (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Sketches, 1960 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - List of Denishawn dances, 1960s, undated (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1920s-1940s (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - "Drums of Peace", 1930s (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Materials for dance dramas, 1930s-1940s (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - "The Seven Purposes of the 'Friends of the Dance' Inc.", 1943 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Ballet of the States, undated (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Materials for dance dramas, undated (Box 79, Folder 7)